

# DAVID VILELA

### PHD INDUSTRIAL ENGINEER

I'm an industrial engineer specialized in civil engineering with seven years of research experience in the mechanical engineering branch, more precisely in implementation of multibody simulators applied to virtual reality, vehicle simulation, mechanisms and machinery. I've worked on the development of real-time vehicle models for hardware-in-the-loop platforms and my PhD thesis was focused on contact models and collision detection for virtual assembly, including a stay at the Computer Graphics and Virtual Reality Group from the University of Bremen, specialized on computer graphics, artificial vision, virtual reality and natural user interfaces. I've also developed hardware and control software for haptic interfaces and I've teached Computer Assisted Design at the University of A Coruña.

I am particularly interested in new technologies: machine learning an Al, blockchain and decentralized systems, robotics, autonomous vehicles, networks and communications, simulations, videogames and virtual and augmented reality.

I am a great enthusiast of science and divulgation, the aerospatial industry, physics and mathematics, music, design, LEGO blocks and I'm fascinated by the human brain and how things work, as well as explaining and teaching them.

#### CONTACT

(+34) 650 230 560

dvilelaf@gmail.com

www.dvilela.info

#### **EXPERIENCE**

2019 - Present	Mechanical Engineering Laboratory, UDC Research support technician
2014 - 2018	Mechanical Engineering Laboratory, UDC FPI Predoctoral Researcher and PhD Teaching Assistant
2017	Computer Graphics Group, University of Bremen PhD student on international stay
2012 - 2014	Mechanical Engineering Laboratory, UDC Research assistant
2011	Department for Urban Planning, Town Hall, Cedeira Internship student
2007	Civil Protection, Cedeira Stage assembly, light and sound installations and security staff

#### **EDUCATION**

2014 - 2018	PhD in Industrial Engineering University of A Coruña
2012 - 2013	Industrial Engineering Research Master's Degree University of A Coruña
2003 - 2011	Industrial Engineering Master's Degree University of A Coruña

## **COURSES AND ACTIVITIES**

2014	C1 Certificate in Advanced English Cambridge School	
2013	Introduction to Python University of A Coruña	20 hours
2011	Introduction to Artificial Intelligence Stanford University	8 weeks (online)
	Introduction to Machine Learning Stanford University	8 weeks (online)
	Child Education and Support Volunteering Nepal Sonríe NGO	3 weeks
2008	Welding Navantia Ferrol	20 hours
2004	C programming	50 hours
2003	Coastal Skipper Nautical and Fishing School, Ferrol	
2002	Basic and Intermediate English Official School of Languages, Cedeira	4 years
2001	AutoCad	30 hours

#### **SKILLS**

Development	C++, C, Python, Fortran, Matlab/Octave, Labview, HTML/CSS, GNU/Linux
Design and edition	Solid Edge, Solid Works, Blender, AutoCad, Inkscape Gimp
Languages	English, Spanish, Galician
Artistic	Guitar
Other	Driving license